Well, this is surprising. Out of all the
advancements I would have expected would
be made, being able to restore the
capacity to learn and cellular activity
in brain tissue after it's been
cryogenically preserved was just not one
of them. Now, people are running with
this in all sorts of interesting
directions, including just the capacity
to cryopreserve a brain, as well as
being able to upload a brain to a
computer. And we will talk about it. It
gets weird. I do want to preface this
and say that these are not necessarily
realistic applications, but we're a step
closer to them, and I would not have
thought this paper was possible.
Researchers decided to focus their
investigation on the hippocampus. This
is the part of your brain that's
responsible for learning and memory. If
any part of it could demonstrate the
capacity to learn, it would be that
part. Now, they did a couple of
different kinds of experiments. One of
them involved taking just brain tissue
from the hippocampus of a mouse. The
other one was in situ, so inside of the
skull of a mouse. And that did present
some additional challenges. They
replaced the blood with a cryoprotectant
and then flash froze the tissue and kept
it frozen between 1 and 8 days. They
revived it, took the cryoprotectant out,
and put it in a medium that would
resemble cerebrospinal fluid. And for
the in situ one, they took the
hippocampus from the rest of the tissue
and put that in the final fluid. They
found that, yes, not only was it able to
maintain spontaneous electrical
activity, but it was capable of
learning. Now, the method they used is
not dissimilar to our little brain
friends. Yes, the brain organoids, the
tiny human brains you can grow in a
literal jar if you want to. You see,
they can be hooked up to electronics. It
needs to have a two-way street where you
can communicate with the little brains
and then they can respond. The responses
they gave indicated that they are able
to change their electrical pattern based
on their input, meaning they retain the
capacity to learn, reinforce pathways,
and make new pathways. That is
incredible. This means that the capacity
to learn and grow is still there after
they've been frozen. Now, some would
like to apply this to reviving brains
after they've been cryopreserved, and I
think that's less realistic than
uploading your mind to a computer, to be
perfectly honest. Neural activity is not
the same thing as function, and your
brain only really functions in the
context of having everything else around
it. Well, yes, you can grow a brain
outside of a skull, but that's not the
function of an adult brain. It's a
miniaturized version. But, this is a
step closer to that goal, I guess. More
than likely, this is going to be applied
to neuroscience as a new way to preserve
samples, rather than any radical medical
application. But, why do people think
that this applies to uploading your
mind? Well, that has a little bit to do
with this paper. Researchers were able
to model an entire mouse brain. Yes, all
26 billion synapses and 9 million
artificial neurons. That means the
spiking activity of every single
individual neuron was displayed. In
fact, they could even communicate with
each other. But, some of the comments
that one of the authors has been saying
leaves pause. I think it is entirely
possible for a piece of hardware to be a
thinking, feeling entity. I really don't
know how to say his name correctly, but
you can look him up. The argument is
that if we can construct an entire
mouse's brain in a virtual world, if we
can run every single spiking neuron, and
watch it learn and grow, perhaps we
could get it to be conscious. But, if we
could do that, then you could scan a
person's brain and create a digital copy
of it. Now, the kind of scale that is
required to run a mouse's brain is
basically an entire warehouse worth of
supercomputer. Researchers are trying to
do the very same thing with a human
brain. If they can do that and create an
AI of sorts that's based on neuromorphic
computation with every single neuron in
a brain working, what is the difference
between that and our brains? If we
accomplish this as humanity, we might
just find out. The reason that people
want to apply this to cryopreservation
of brains is that if we can preserve the
neural activity, perhaps we can scan it
and upload it rather than trying to get
a cryopreserved brain back online,
perhaps we can turn it into an AI. This
is not real immortality because if you
copy yourself in two or three or 10 of
you can all exist at the same time, you
have not achieved immortality. You have
simply copied yourself at best
and at worst created a suffering
intelligence.
I don't know what's going to happen
next. It will be interesting and I hope
it leads to robots having rights.
Follow me for more.